A Guide to the American Society of International Law records, Howard M. Holtzmann papers FA1872
Rockefeller Archive Center
American Society of International Law records, Howard M. Holtzmann papers
1885-2014
Rockefeller Archive Center
American Society of International Law
Holtzmann, Howard M.
FA1872
77.35 Cubic Feet 162 legal document boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
Arranged in 10 series by subject.
Series I: Correspondence, 1923-2011. Series II: Writings. Series III: Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, 1981-2009. Series IV: United Nations Commission on International Trade Law, 1974-2011. Series V: American Arbitration Association, 1968-2012. Series VI: Arbitration, 1973-2013. Series VII: Organizations, 1957-2010. Series VIII: Claims Resolution Tribunal, 1997-2002. Series IX: Business, 1973-2013. Series X: Personal, 1941-2012.
Scope and Contents
The Howard M. Holtzmann papers document the life and work of Judge Howard M. Holtzmann, and help to tell the story of international commercial arbitration and conciliation through the lens of one of its foremost experts and practitioners.
Judge Holtzmann helped to develop and codify many of the precepts and protocols of international arbitration and mass claims processes through his landmark work as an arbitrator with international organizations such as the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, the United Nations Commission on International Trade Law, the Claims Resolution Tribunal for Dormant Accounts in Switzerland, and the American Arbitration Association, as well as in private practice with the firm Holtzmann, Sheppard, and Wise.
- Correspondence, 1923-2011; I; 7.53 Cubic Feet 16 legal document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the correspondence and memos written and received by Judge Holtzmann, in both a professional and personal capacity. Included herein are groupings of correspondence organized by Holtzmann. The bulk of the correspondence ranges from the 1970s through the first decade of the 2000s.
  - Arranged by Howard M. Holtzmann, 1982-2002; 1
    This subseries contains correspondence created and arranged by Holtzmann for his personal records.
    Arrangement
    Original order as created by Holtzmann. Files are primarily grouped together as Chronological Files, and in other select thematic groupings.
    - Howard M. Holtzmann Chronological Files, 1982-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1-10, Box 2, Folder 1-8, Box 3, Folder 1-9)
    - Howard M. Holtzmann Chronological Files, 1982-1993 (Box 4, Folder 1-9, Box 5, Folder 1A, 1-8, Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - General Correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Yale, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Peace Palace, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Howard M. Holtzmann CV, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - ICCA, 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 1995 January 1-April 30 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - 1995 May 1-September 30 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
    - 1995 October 15-December (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - 1996 January-June (Box 7, Folder 9, Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - 1996 July-December (Box 8, Folder 9-10, Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1997 May-July (Box 8, Folder 4-8)
    - 1997 September-December (Box 9, Folder 2-6)
    - 1998 January-March (Box 9, Folder 7-9, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1998 April-June (Box 10, Folder 2-4)
    - 1998 July-September (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
    - 1998 October-December (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
    - 1999 (Box 10, Folder 10, Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - 1999 July-September (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
    - 1999 October-December (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - 2000 January-June (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
    - 2000 July-December (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - 2001 January-June (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Mass Claims Steering Committee, 2000-2005 (Box 12, Folder 3-8, Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Mass Claims, 2000s, 2006-2009 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Mass Claims Steering Committee, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    - Mass Claims, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - General, 1923-2011; 2
    This subseries consists of the general correspondence and memos of Holtzmann.
    Arranged as received, primarily by broad thematic groupings.
    - American Bar Association Program on Arbitration, 1975-1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Art Collections, 1994-2000 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Concertgebouw, Amsterdam, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Delphi - Yacht, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Denning Program Publications, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Emails - General and Miscellaneous, 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - Gerlach, Contracts, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Holtzmann, Anne F., 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - International Bar Association, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - International Peace Academy, 1974-1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Koh, Harold Hongju, 2010 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - University of Virginia, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - William Penn Life Insurance, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1920s, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1940s, 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1950s, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1970s, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 7-10)
    - 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 14, Folder 11-12, Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 2000s, 2009-2011 (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
- Writings, II; 15.66 Cubic Feet 29 legal document boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
  This series contains the manuscripts and typescript drafts, notes, correspondence, and research and reference material pertaining to some of Judge Holtzmann's published and unpublished writings.
  - The Papers of Howard M. Holtzmann, 1969-2010; 1
    Original order by Holtzmann, as received, transcribed by his assistants.
    Contains Volumes I-VI of Holtzmann's selected papers, as well as speech materials, personal papers, and general papers. Contained are both the transcriptions and the original manuscripts and typescripts.
    - Chronological Index, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 3A)
    - HMH Archives, Scanned, 1974-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4-5)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Arbitration in Arising out of Long-Term Collaboration Agreements between Companies from Different Countries, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Remunerating of Arbitrators Introductory Notes, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Opening Remarks of HMH at First Session of Moscow Congress, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Communication on Arbitration and Contracts Concerned with Scientific Research and Technical Work, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Communication on Arbitration and Contract Guarantees, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Communication to be Presented at the Concluding Session of the Fourth International Congress on Arbitration, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Achievements of the Fourth International Congress on Arbitration - A Report from Moscow, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Arbitration Clauses - Valuable Methods for Solving Business Problems Arising in Long-Term Business Arrangements, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - The Use of Impartial Technical Experts to Resolve Engineering and Other Technological Disputes before Arbitration, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Report of Commercial Arbitration Committee to 1973 Annual Meeting of Council of Section of Corporation, Banking and Business Law, American Bar Association (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Information on Audio Cassette Tape on 1973 Legal Developments in Doing Business Abroad (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - New Uses for Arbitration in Soviet-American Contracts for Industrial, Scientific, and Technical Development, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Comments Concerning Negotiations Between U.S. Corporations and Soviet Foreign Trading Organizations, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - The Anglo-Saxon Case from the American Point of View, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Arbitration in East-West Trade, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Motion of the American Arbitration Association for Leave to File a Brief as Amicus Curiae, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - The Value of Arbitration and Mediation in Resolving Community and Racial Disputes Affecting Business - An Overview, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Comments on Preliminary Draft of UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Hypothetical Case - To Illustrate the Use of Arbitration to Fill Gaps in Long-Term International Commercial Transactions, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Arbitration of East-West Trade Disputes, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Arbitration in Long-Term Business Transactions, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Transcripts - Vol I - Study of Swedish Arbitration Law and Practice, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Panel Discussion on Arbitration, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Introductions of the Subjects of the Four Working Parties, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Powers of Arbitrators under US Law to Fill Gaps Arising Under Long-Term Commercial Contracts, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Subject - Techniques for Resolving Problems in Forming and Performing Long-Term Contracts, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - The Desirability of Including More Specific Provisions Concerning Place of Arbitration in the Model Clause in the UNCITRAL Rules, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - The Relative Importance of Trade Usage in the UNCITRAL Rules, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Achievements of the New Delhi Congress, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Settlement of Investment Disputes in East-West Trade, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Private Conflict Resolution Including the Problems of Business in Meeting Challenges of Community Responsibility - Methods and Techniques with Particular Reference to Housing - Opening Remarks, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Arbitration - An Indispensable Aid to Multinational Enterprise, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts - Vol II - Resolving Disputes in US-China Trade, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Addendum Concerning Option of UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Subject - The New UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Arbitrating International Commercial Cases in England - New Developments and Old Differences, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Report of Commercial Arbitration Committee to 1977 Mid-Winter Meeting of Council of Section of Corporation, Banking and Business Law, American Bar Association (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - United States of America - The American Arbitration Association, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - The Importance of Choosing the Right Place to Arbitrate an International Case, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Summary of Remarks by HMH, Alternative Representative of the US at United Nations Commission on International Trade Law, Tenth Session, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - United States Entry in "International Council for Commercial Arbitration Yearbook", 1977 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Arbitration and the Courts - Partners in a System of International Justice, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - New Arbitration Clause for Optional Use in US-USSR Trade, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Future Work on International Commercial Arbitration and Conciliation, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - The Key Choices in International Arbitration - Issues and Developments, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - Grounds for Refusing Enforcement of Awards Under the Convention on the Recognition and Enforcement of Foreign Arbitral Awards, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Transcripts - Vol III - The Lawyer as Negotiator - Problems, Readings, and Materials, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Export Sales Contracts - Enforcement Problems, Arbitration Provisions, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Achievements of the Sixth International Congress on Arbitration - A Report from Mexico City, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Dispute Resolution Procedures in East-West Trade, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Study of Austrian Arbitration Law and Practice, undated (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Opening Remarks of HMH at Program of American Law Institute-American Bar Association, 1979 October 19 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Editors Note about "A New Look at Legal Aspects of Doing Business with China - Developments a Year after Recognition", 2010 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Conciliation - A Promising Procedure for Resolving Multiparty Disputes, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Whether, When, Where, and How to Arbitrate in International Cases, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - The UNCITRAL Arbitration Rules, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Key Choices to be Made in Determining How to Resolve International Commercial Disputes - The Lawyer's Viewpoint on Whether, When, Where, and How to Arbitrate, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Introduction - Recent Contributions of Pieter Sanders to the Art of International Commercial Arbitration, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Enforcing Arbitral Awards, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - The Conduct of Arbitral Proceedings Under the Draft UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Address by HMH at the signing of the agreement establishing a Model Clause for Arbitration in Vienna of Disputes in US-Hungarian Trade, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Editor's Note on Article from "International Handbook on Commercial Arbitration", 2010 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Introductory Note to the American Code of Ethics for Arbitrators in Commercial Disputes, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - Remarks of HMH at Meeting to Welcome New Iranian Members of Tribunal 22, 1985 January (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - What an Arbitrator Can Do to Overcome Delays in International Arbitration, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Transcripts - Vol IV - The Iran-United States Claims Tribunal - It's Lessons for International Business Lawyers, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Some Lessons of the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - The Role of Dispute Resolution in Facilitating International Trade and Investment, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - ICCA, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Five Ways the American Arbitration Association Can Assist in Resolving Disputes in Trade with the Soviet Union, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Introduction to the New Commercial Arbitration Rules of the American Arbitration Association, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - International Commercial Dispute Settlement - Developments of a Decade, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Celebration of the 30th Anniversary of the Italian Arbitration Association, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - The Arbitral Process and the Independence of Arbitrators, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Dispute Resolution Under the UNCITRAL Conciliation Rules, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Setting Aside Arbitral Awards - The Common Law Viewpoint, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Introduction to the Mutual Cooperation Agreement between the Permanent Court of Arbitration and the ICCA, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Editors Note on "Yearbook Commercial Arbitration" (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - A Guide to the UNCITRAL Model Law on International Commercial Arbitration - Legislative History and Commentary, undated (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Fact-Finding by the Iran-United States Claims Tribunal, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - How to Prevent DelaTy and Disruption of Arbitration - Lessons of the 1990 ICCA Stockholm Congress (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Dispute Resolution in Europe Under the UNCITRAL Conciliation Rules, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Powers and Duties of Arbitrators in Disputes that Include Issues of Competition Law - The New United States View, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - The Geopolitics of Arbitration, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Comments in Response to the Questionnaire in the Secretary General's Background Paper, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Transcripts - Vol V - Some Lessons from the Awards of the Iran-US Claims Tribunal that may be Useful in Disputes concerning the Termination of Joint Ventures, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Balancing the Need for Certainty and Flexibility in International Arbitration Procedures, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - The Cook Who Eats His Own Soup - Experiences of a Judge Applying a Legal Text Co-Drafted by Him, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - A Proposal for Future UNCITRAL Work on Arbitration, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Should Bermuda's International Arbitration Law Be Changed - If So, How, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Key Factors for the Success of Uniform International Commercial Legal Texts, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Editor's Note on "Yearbook Commercial Arbitration, Volume XVI", 1991 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Adoption of a New Egyptian Arbitration Law, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Some Reflections on the Nature of Arbitration, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Remarks on the Inauguration of the Bahrain International Commercial Arbitration Centre, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - International Commercial Arbitration, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - An Introduction to the UNCITRAL Model Law, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - A Task for the 21st Century - Creating a New International Court for Resolving Disputes on the Enforceability of Arbitral Awards, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - The Tribunal's Use of Experts, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Transcripts - Vol VI - Recent Legislation that Combines Conciliation and Arbitration, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Editor's Note on the In the Matter of United Steelworkers, 2010 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - In the Matter of the United Steel Workers of America-CIO and Various Steel and Iron Ore Companies, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Report of the Committee on Federal Constitution, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - International Committee for Commercial Arbitration - Statement of Purposes and Procedures, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Statement of Purposes and Procedures of International Council for Commercial Arbitration, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Correspondence with Pieter Sanders, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Code of Ethics for Arbitrators in Commercial Disputes, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Documents Exchanged Between American Arbitration Association, USSR Chamber of Commerce and Industry and Stockholm Chamber of Commerce, 1977 January 12 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Questionnaire for for Organizations Seeking Consultative Status with the Economic and Social Council, undated (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Stockholm Congress Plan for Working Group I, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Subjects to Be Considered by the Group of Experts, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Introduction, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Remarks, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - The Lauterquack Lectures I - Arbitration and the Truncated Family: Separability or Denial of Justice, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - The Lauterquack Lectures II - New Developments in International Commercial Arbitration, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - The Very Last Intermezzo, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Remarks at Constitution Day Dinner, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Correspondence with Robert MacCrate, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - American Community Council Thanksgiving Day Service, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Commencement Jewish Theological Seminary of America, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Commemorative Tribute to Dr. Albert Bowers, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - The Peace Palace, Home of Arbitration, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - An International Judge at the Hague, undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - A Celebration of the Life of Richard B. Fisher, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - "A Braggiotti Birthday Ballad", 1992 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - The Second Annual Yale Jewish Alumni Forum "Jewish Life at Yale: Then and Now", Reunion Weekend, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - General Papers and Personal Papers - Remarks at Polytechnic Preparatory Country Day School Special Reunion, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Papers - Introduction to "Occident and Orient", 1988 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous Papers - A Prediction for the 21st Century and the Next 100 Years, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous Papers - Centripetal and Centrifugal Forces in Modern Arbitration, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous Papers - Correspondence with Mary Catherine, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous Papers - Speech by HMH, 2000 July 10 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous Papers - Thank You Skal, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Speech Materials - Book 1 - Some Lessons from Awards of the Iran-US Claims Tribunal that May be Useful in Disputes Concerning the Termination of Joint Ventures, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Speech Materials - Book 1 - Introduction to Iran-US Tribunal, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Speech Materials - Book 1 - The First Code of Ethics for Arbitrators in Commercial Disputes, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Speech Materials - Book 1 - Article 9 - Arbitration Agreement and Interim Measures by Court, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)